我们在零重力之中起舞
We can dance in zero G
飞速旅行到遥远的星际
Traveling fast far from galaxy
需要特殊的快递吗
Need a special delivery
只需叫上Malo Korrigan
Just call Malo Korrigan
但不是免费的
But it's not free
Malo Korrigan
没人能打倒你
Nobody will bring you down
Malo Korrigan
生活在宇宙中
live in space
翻译、时间轴、后期：Bolshevik0
#7          鲜活的记忆
Mr. York.
York先生
Yes, it's a Z captor.
没错 这是个Z捕捉器
But this is a weapon designed for...
但这个武器是
For a memory seeker Devourer.
为记忆吞噬者研发的
Exactly.
没错
But I thought the League
但是我以为星际联盟
have forbidden the fabrication of memory eaters.
已经禁止了记忆吞噬者的生产
The members of the Consortium decided a very long time ago
财团的成员很早以前就决定了
that they did not have to obey all of the League's decrees, Mr. York.
他们不必遵守星际联盟的所有法律 York先生
And besides we had a use for a seeker.
更何况我们使用它
This particular one was built to
这个特殊版本是用来
absorb the memory of someone like Senator Herron.
吸收一类人比如参议员Herron的记忆
Herron?
Herron吗
Wasn't he going to be
难道他不是
in charge of the investigation into the Consortium?
负责调查财团的那位吗
That's right.
没错
But since then he's had a change of heart.
在那之后他改了主意
Every man has his price.
每个人都能被一定的金钱买通
And if I've understood
如果我想的没错
after having absorbed your scientists memory
你的记忆吞噬者在吸收完你们的科学家的记忆之后
your seeker managed to escape
设法逃走
and now it's heading for a target
而现在奔向的目标
that in the meantime has gone over to your side.
正是已经倒向你们这边的人
You catch on quickly, Mr. York.
你理解得很快 York先生
注:
Yoga Carcharias是Yoga的全名
And that is why I also have my price, Mr. Carcharias.
这就是为什么我也有我的价格 Carcharias先生
Bring me back the memory seeker Devourer, Mr. York.
帮我把记忆吞噬者找回来吧 York先生
And I will pay you the price we agreed upon.
我就会把约定好的金额付给你
I will have it in my possession long before it reaches its target.
在它碰到参议员之前我就会抓住它
Senator Herron.
参议员Herron
Don't forget that after the session,
别忘了在会议之后
you have a meeting with the Energy Commission
你要和能源委员会的人开会
at League headquarters.
在星际联盟总部
I never forget anything my friend
我什么都不会忘记的 我的朋友
and you're here to remind me of that.
因为你总是在这儿提醒我
Eh...
呃
After, you have a reception at Lincoln...
之后 有个招待会会在林肯
You can cancel that.
你可以取消它
Afterwards I'm leaving for the Astra Holton going on a cruise.
之后我想去Astra Holton观光
Very well, senator.
好吧 参议员
Attention all in twelve and then you get on the Phoenix Nebula.
一直注意着12点方向 你就会到达凤凰星云
Hey, Roberta,
嘿 Roberta
you still haven't told me where to get fuel for me on Dala System.
你还是没告诉我如何在Dala星系中补充燃料
Told me of.
跟我说
You'll find someone Angel Stern for Dolores.
你会在Dolores那儿找到一个人叫Angel Stern
But be careful, it is a little more expensive.
不过要注意了 这个价格有点贵
It's me like sweetie pie.
亲爱的是我
Do you have shortcut those at the bar
在吧那里你有什么捷径
to give it to your favorite space tracers there?
把东西送给最好的太空牛仔
You go by Angel Stern
你可以去找Angel Stern
while you're there you can help Dolores full of our tank, okay?
同时帮Dolores补充我们的燃料 行吗
Oh yeah yeah you're vicious Mike. Come on, my sweet...
哦 这里是你恶毒的Mike 亲爱的
Roberta, this is ridiculous.
Roberta 这太可笑了
May I remind you
需要我提醒你
that you're coming with us to send those to have a day off.
你是跟我们一道休一天假的吗
And do some shopping.
然后去购物
Everybody I can't remember where Jen far is this time of year.
大家 我不记得今年的Jen far在哪了
Could you help me out ah?
能跟我说一下吗
On the other side of Alba Khair, you space cadet.
在Alba Khair的另一端 你这个太空菜鸡
Ah, you're the best Roberta.
啊 我最棒的Roberta
I love you if I wasn't married.
如果我没结婚的话我肯定爱上你了
No you don't you're just like the others.
不 你肯定和其他人一样
It's my memory you love.
你们爱的是我的记忆
Without me you'd all be lost.
没有我 你们肯定会迷路
You sorry excuses for space tracers.
爱我的这个说法不过是你们太空牛仔的借口
Hey, walking encyclopedia.
嘿 活的百科全书
You're ready to go?
可以出发了吗
You bet I'm ready.
我保证已经好了
Hey, wait, Roberta.
嘿 等一下 Roberta
How do we get through the First Alba Khair?
我们怎么通过第一Alba Khair
There's a magnetic storm on Phoenix.
凤凰星云那儿有个磁暴
How do I get around it?
怎么绕路
Listen, I want to be able to...
听着 我想
Stop!
安静
Listen carefully, tracers.
听好了 牛仔们
I'm taking my only day off of the year.
我正在度今年唯一的一天假期
So for just a few short hours,
所以接下来短暂的数个小时内
figure out there for yourselves.
你们自己去解决问题吧
I just have one more thing to ask you.
我还有一个问题要问你
When overstating is so long.
向过度的同情心说再见
Let's shop it around.
我们来购物吧
The good thing about a senator is that
参议员的一个优点在于
you always know where to find him.
你总能轻易地找到他
What else do I need today?
我今天还需要点什么
No more.
不需要了
Have pity on us.
同情一下我们吧
All right but on one condition,
好的 不过还有一项要求
注:
根据维基百科，Xanthos是星际联盟的首都，也就是Roberta现在所处的位置
let's walk through the aquatic gardens of the Xanthos one last time.
我们最后再走一次Xanthos的水上花园吧
Greetings, senator.
参议员你好
Ah, there's Herron.
啊 那就是Herron
And if the seeker was programmed properly,
如果吞噬者制作得没问题的话
it shouldn't be too far behind the senator.
它肯定在参议员身后不远的地方
Where is it?
到底在哪儿
Come on show yourself.
快出来吧
Thank you for a wonderful day off.
谢谢你们陪我度过一个如此美妙的假日
Now I feel ready to return to my holographic screen,
现在我觉得我准备好回去<del>蹲守在全息屏幕前面</del>办公了
refreshed and energized.
完全恢复 充满活力
Roberta!
Roberta
We must be out of there, senator.
我们得赶快离开这儿 参议员
Quickly!
快点儿
Who is that woman?
那个女的是谁啊
Roberta!
Roberta
Roberta are you okay?
Roberta 你还好吗
Uh-huh, who's Roberta?
呃 谁是Roberta
A memory seeker Devourer.
那是个记忆吞噬者
All right, what's going on over here?
这发生了什么事
You're all going to show me some identification.
你们的身份证件都需要让我看看<del>（震声</del>
Another time, pal.
下次再说吧 伙计
A civilian just stole the vehicle in Sector B41.
在B41区 一个平民刚刚偷了个载具
I need backup now.
我需要后援
It's impossible, Malo.
Malo 这是不可能的
We will never find the shadow truck in all this traffic.
我们不可能在这么多道路上找到那个阴影飞船
Not doing it ourselves we want.
当然不是光靠我们自己
And now for all you space tracers out there in the galaxy,
太空牛仔们注意了
It's time to listen up.
大家听好了
Malo Korrigan is taking over the airwaves.
Malo Korrigan要说几句话
Tracers, I have some bad news.
牛仔们 我有些坏消息
Roberta's entire memory has been wiped out
Roberta的记忆
by a memory seeker Devourer.
被记忆吞噬者完全抹消
No more maps and no more Roberta.
没有地图也没有Roberta了
I don't need to remind you how vital the tracer map is for all of us.
不需要我说 你们也知道牛仔地图对我们有多重要
As for Roberta, my memory serves me well.
至于Roberta 我记得很清楚
She's been our friend since forever.
她一直以来都是我们的朋友
I think that we can still help her.
我认为我们还能帮到她
But to do it,
但是想做到这件事
we will need to get our hands
我们需要和你们一道努力
on a red shadow truck left Xanthos in one heck of a hurry.
立刻去找一个刚离开Xanthos的红色影子飞船
I say we should all get back on the starways
我觉得我们应该立刻回到太空中
and help Malo find out truck.
帮助Malo找到那个飞船
Let's have a look at the memories
让我看看这些
that this awful machine has devoured.
被这个糟糕的机器吞噬的记忆
The creature eating its creator.
这个生物正在吃它的制造者
What about that woman from the Senate gardens?
那个出现在参议院花园的女士呢
Thor system.
雷神星系
Planet Malvika.
Malvika行星
Coordinates TXH89-543.
坐标TXH89-543
Mr. Carcharias, I've got you a seeker.
Carcharias先生 我抓到你那个吞噬者了
And I have something else
不过还有些别的东西
that will no doubt be of interest to you.
是你肯定感兴趣的那种
The tracers space map.
牛仔们的太空地图
The...The tracers map?
牛仔地图吗
But how did you manage to get your...
那你是怎么
It's not important.
这不重要
What does matter is what you're willing to do to have the map
现在有意义的事是你想怎样拿到地图
since it wasn't discussed in our agreement.
因为这并不在我们的协议当中
I suppose you already have some idea, Mr. York.
我认为你已经有些主意了 York先生
Yes, an idea with one million Yellows.
没错 一个100万Yellow的主意
We will meet on planet Malvika in the Thor system.
我们在雷神星系的Malvika行星上会面吧
You bring me the money and I'll give you the memory seeker.
我们一手交钱一手交货
Malvika with the asteroid barrier that surrounds the planet.
Malvika是个有着小行星屏障环绕的行星
That would be suicide.
这无异于自杀
You're forgetting one thing.
你忘了件事
We're the ones with the space map now.
我们现在有牛仔地图了
Not the tracers.
而不是那些太空牛仔们
The shadow truck just got off starway 5XB.
影子飞船刚刚离开了5XB星际通道
Coordinates TXH89-543.
坐标是TXH89-543
It's too fast for me.
太快了 我追不上
Don't worry about it, Dolores.
Dolores 别担心
We're on it.
我们去追
And thank you.
谢谢你
注:
这里的坐标应该是TXH89-543，估计是配音口胡了
Alright, TXH89-43.
好的 TXH89-43
You know where that is Cyana?
Cyana 你知道那是哪儿吗
Planet Malvika. It's in the Thor system.
行星Malvika 在雷神星系里
Malvika? That's impossible.
Malvika 这不可能
That will be guaranteed self-destruction!
这肯定会变成自杀行为
Thor system.
雷神星系
Planet Malvika.
Malvika行星
What happens next?
接下来呢
I'm connected your system to the tracer map now.
我会把你的系统连接到牛仔地图上
注:
这里应该是一个球坐标系
Enter the asteroid barrier at 24 degrees east, 50 degrees north.
以24度偏东 50度偏北方向进入到小行星屏障
The speed of the first asteroid is 0.34c.
第一颗小行星的速度是0.34倍光速
Perfect, I'm going in.
完美 我这就进去
The shadow truck has already entered the asteroid barrier.
影子飞船已经进入到小行星屏障里了
And it's got company.
而且还有个同伴
This is our only chance to get Roberta's memory back.
如果想拿回Roberta的记忆 这是我们唯一的机会
Space rocks or not.
做个好汉还是放弃
There are too many things I'd forget if you weren't around.
如果你不在的话 我会忘记很多东西
So I'm willing to take the risk.
所以我愿意承担这个风险
I hope you haven't come empty-handed.
我希望你没有空手而来
The money will be transferred as soon as I give the vocal command.
只要我得到语音指令 这些钱就会立刻转给你
And here's the Z captor.
而这个就是Z捕捉器
It's all in there.
都在这儿了
alors on ne dit on travaille bien maintenant on vase poser
我们现在做的不好也不会去问Roberta了
quand trois gros chèque plusieurs autour de nous accompagner
因为有三个探测器陪伴着我们
Fantastique
这真是极好的
il y en a moins axant leur fameuse carte du traceur pouravoir droit au chômage
在得到这有名的牛仔地图前 我们得到过一些牛仔使用的地图
et le consortium à toute sa dimension
而这些地图帮助财团变得强大了起来
Ah...What about the vocal command?
呃 那语音指令呢
Transfer.
转移
I'm sorry. I must have given the wrong vocal command.
真抱歉 我肯定给错了语音指令
You...betrayed...me.
你 背叛 了我
No one renegotiates my agreements.
没人会和我重新谈协议
You can get up, York.
York 你可以起来了
You've been very useful to me.
你做的很好
And that's why I have decided to let you live.
这就是为什么我决定让你活下来
Yago Carcharias is having scruples.
Yago Carcharias居然在可怜别人
Now I've seen it all.
现在我全看见了
I'm warning you right now that I don't have any.
我现在立刻警告你我可是毫无怜悯之心
How could you have possibly gotten through the asteroid barrier
在不使用牛仔地图的情况下
without using the tracer map?
你们怎么可能通过这个小行星屏障
Well, that's just one of the many things
诶 这不过是你不知道的
that you'll never understand, Yago.
许多事中的一件而已 Yago
If you're not as dumb as I think you are,
如果你没有我想的那么愚蠢
you should be able to put these plugs
你应该把这些螺钉插上
I removed from your engine back into it.
我刚从你的引擎上卸下来
You can't leave us here like this.
你们不能就这样抛弃我们
We'll never be able to get through the asteroid barrier.
我们永远也不能通过这个小行星屏障
Turn on your radios.
打开你的收音机
Roberta will tell you how.
Roberta会告诉你怎么做
You just have to pray that she recovers her memory.
你只需要祈祷她恢复了记忆
Let him go.
让他走吧
I know Malo well.
我很了解Malo
He always keeps his word.
他总是遵守承诺
All right.
好吧
Come back to us, Roberta.
快回来吧 Roberta
Rico to Starduke, how do you get from at the jetty door after 12...
Rico呼叫星爵号 你们是怎么离开码头的
Rico do you have any idea
Rico你可知道
what kind of ordeal we've just been through?
我们今天经历了怎样的困难险阻
Yeah,
恩
I hear the Malo say something
在牛仔电台上
about a little problem on the tracer radio.
我听Malo说过了他那点小问题
I'm not sure what it was.
我不太清楚那是啥
But now I'm really really lost.
但我现在确实迷路了
Head for the Sombrero Galaxy.
去阔边帽星系
Go along cosmic filament 32 until the red Vega Vortex, eh,
沿着星际窄路32号走 直到红色的织女星座 呃
and you'll be there before you know it.
你就会在你知道怎么到那儿之前到那儿
Hey, what about your promise to Yago?
嘿 你对Yago的承诺如何了
Sometimes I just don't understand you well, Korrigan.
Korrigan 我有时候就是不能理解你
If we use the same methods as Yago and the Consortium,
如果我采用和Yago和他的财团一样的手段
we're not different from them, Jonas.
我们和他们就没什么不同了 Jonas
So we're gonna keep our promise
所以我们就要遵守承诺
and we're going to bring this thing to the nearest post Zuider office.
同时我们要把这个玩意儿送给最近的警察局
And someone's going to have to explain
然后有些人就得解释
why they were in possession of an illegal biomechanical weapon.
为何他们会拥有一个非法的生物机械武器
Ah, it's good to be back home again.
啊 回到家的感觉真好
Surprise!
想不到吧<del>.jpg</del>
Welcome to home, Roberta!
欢迎回家 Roberta
Am I late?
我来迟了吗
Welcome home, Roberta.
欢迎回家 Roberta
I would have got here sooner
我本来可以来早点的
but the... Oh tell me, how was your day off from the work?
但是 哦 跟我说吧 你那个假日过得怎么样
I did a lot of shopping
我买了很多东西
and as for the rest
至于剩下的部分
I'll have to rely on all of your memories of today.
我现在要依赖于你们的记忆了
From Roser to Jonas, Malo and Cyana, everyone else here.
从Roser到Jonas Malo和Cyana 在场的所有人
Apart from that, all I have to say is routine.
除此之外 我想说的不过是 例行公事
我们在零重力之中起舞
We can dance in zero G
飞速旅行到遥远的星际
Traveling fast far from galaxy
Malo Korrigan
没人能打倒你
Nobody will bring you down
Malo Korrigan
生活在宇宙中
live in space